<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SQL Injection on ByteShifters</title>
    <link>https://byteshifters.com/tags/sql-injection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SQL Injection on ByteShifters</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://byteshifters.com/tags/sql-injection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Advanced SQL Injection Techniques</title>
      <link>https://byteshifters.com/posts/hacking/sql-injections/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://byteshifters.com/posts/hacking/sql-injections/introduction/</guid>
      
      <description>Introduction to Advanced SQL Injection Techniques In the ever-evolving landscape of web security, SQL injection (SQLi) remains one of the most prevalent and effective attack vectors. Understanding the various techniques and strategies for exploiting SQLi vulnerabilities is essential for both attackers and defenders. This document introduces several key topics related to advanced SQL injection techniques, highlighting methods to extract sensitive information, bypass web application firewalls (WAFs), and generate errors from databases.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WAF Bypass Techniques for SQL Injection</title>
      <link>https://byteshifters.com/posts/hacking/sql-injections/waf-bypass-techniques-for-sqli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://byteshifters.com/posts/hacking/sql-injections/waf-bypass-techniques-for-sqli/</guid>
      
      <description>WAF Bypass Techniques for SQL Injection Below are various methods to bypass WAFs and execute SQL injection attacks. Each technique takes advantage of different obfuscation, encoding, and manipulation strategies to evade detection.
1. Using Encoding and Obfuscation URL Encoding %27%20UNION%20SELECT%20NULL,NULL,NULL-- Encode parts of the payload to bypass basic keyword detection mechanisms used by WAFs.
Double URL Encoding %2527%2520UNION%2520SELECT%2520NULL,NULL,NULL-- Double encode the payload to evade more sophisticated detection mechanisms.
Hex Encoding &amp;#39; UNION SELECT 0x61646D696E, 0x70617373776F7264 -- Use hexadecimal encoding for the payload to obscure the SQL commands.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
